<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SeisSol</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on SeisSol</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 17:10:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://seissol.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Imprint</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/imprint/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 12:54:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/imprint/</guid><description>Address Dr. Alice-Agnes Gabriel
Department für Geo- und Umweltwissenschaften, Geophysik
Universität München
Theresienstr. 41
D-80333 München
Liability This site contains links to external sites. Even if we are checking the content of these sites for legality at the time we create the link, we deny any liability for external content. The organisations providing external sites remain fully responsible for the content they provide, even if we provide links to their sites.</description></item><item><title>Highlights</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/about/highlights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 11:36:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/about/highlights/</guid><description>Awards and Honours IWSM 2017 Award Winning Poster. Bauer, Alexander, Fabian Scheipl, Helmut Küchenhoff, and Alice-Agnes Gabriel. (2017), Modeling spatio-temporal earthquake dynamics using generalized functional additive regression, in Proceedings of the 32nd International Workshop on Statistical Modelling, 3-7 July, 2017, Groningen, Netherlands. . 2017 SC17 Best Paper Award, International Supercomputing Conference, Denver, USA. Most prestigious prize for application driven high-performance computing awarding the longest and largest multi-physics simulations performed to date modelling the 2004 Sumatra-Andaman earthquake 2014 ACM Gordon Bell Prize Finalist, Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) at Supercomputing Conference SC14, New Orleans, USA.</description></item><item><title>Researchers Create Largest, Longest Multiphysics Earthquake Simulation to Date</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/researchers-create-largest-longest-multiphysics-earthquake-simulation-to-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/researchers-create-largest-longest-multiphysics-earthquake-simulation-to-date/</guid><description>We were featured in a research highlight of the Gauss Centre for Supercomputing.
Read the full article: https://www.gauss-supercomputing.de/news/research-highlights/article/researchers-create-largest-longest-multiphysics-earthquake-simulation-to-date/</description></item></channel></rss>