<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News Blog on SeisSol</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in News Blog on SeisSol</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 17:10:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://seissol.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Joint SeisSol and ExaHyPE User Workshop, Training and Hackathon - June 11/12, 2026</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/workshop2026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/workshop2026/</guid><description>In celebration of 20 years of SeisSol and 10 years of ExaHyPE, we are happy to announce
The first Joint SeisSol+ExaHyPE User Workshop, A combined SeisSol+ExaHyPE user training The first SeisSol+ExaHyPE Hackathon, taking place on June 11–12, 2026 in Garching (Munich), in the Leibniz Supercomputing Centre (LRZ).
For the user workshop (Jun 11), we call for contributed talks on usage and development of SeisSol or ExaHyPE, and closely related topics.</description></item><item><title>Segment-Jumping Ridgecrest Earthquakes Explored in New Study</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/ridgecrest-study/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/ridgecrest-study/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;On the morning of July 4, 2019, a magnitude 6.4 earthquake struck the Searles Valley in California’s Mojave Desert, with impacts felt across Southern California. About 34 hours later on July 5, the nearby city of Ridgecrest was struck by a magnitude 7.1 earthquake, a jolt felt by millions across the state of California and throughout neighboring communities in Arizona, Nevada, and even Baja California, Mexico. [&amp;hellip;]&amp;quot;
Read the entire article on the Ridgecrest earthquakes and the SeisSol simulations of it at the Scripps Institution of Oceanography&amp;rsquo;s blog: https://scripps.</description></item><item><title>Science Publication on the 2023 Kahramanmaraş Earthquake</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/kahramanmaras/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/kahramanmaras/</guid><description>The SeisSol group at LMU, Munich, and Scripps Institute, San Diego, reports about &amp;ldquo;The complex dynamics of the 2023 Kahramanmaraş, Turkey, Mw 7.8-7.7 earthquake doublet&amp;rdquo; in a research article in Science.
See also the following press release by Scripps:
The Unexpected Physics Behind Turkey’s Devastating 2023 Earthquakes On 6th of February 2023, a Mw 7.8 earthquake broke more than 300 km of the East Anatolian Fault, Turkey. Nine hours later, a second earthquake of Mw 7.</description></item><item><title>SeisSol Revealed as Mystery Application at the Student Cluster Competition 2022</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-scc22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-scc22/</guid><description>At the SC22 Supercomputing Conference, the Student Cluster Competition has revealed SeisSol as its &amp;ldquo;Mystery Application&amp;rdquo;. In 2022, 13 student teams again take part in a 48-hour live contest to compute HPC workloads on their compute clusters. While participants could prepare for most of the SCC applications over the summer, the Mystery Application is only revealed when the cluster competition has started.
We&amp;rsquo;re proud to introduce SeisSol as this year&amp;rsquo;s Mystery Application.</description></item><item><title>Years-Long Collaboration Helps Geophysicists Better Understand Severe Earthquake-Tsunami Risks</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/collaboration_gcs2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/collaboration_gcs2022/</guid><description>The Gauss Centre for Supercomputing featured an article about the successful LMU+TUM collaboration on SeisSol - read the full article here: https://www.gauss-centre.eu/news/research-highlights/years-long-collaboration-helps-geophysicists-better-understand-severe-earthquake-tsunami-risks/</description></item><item><title>Paper on 3D Acoustic-Elastic Coupling with Gravity Accepted for SC21 Conference</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-sc21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:40:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-sc21/</guid><description>As part of the ChEESE project, we realised a Pilot Demonstrator for simulating tsunami-earthquake interaction. The respective paper on &amp;ldquo;3D Acoustic-Elastic Coupling with Gravity: The Dynamics of the 2018 Palu, Sulawesi Earthquake and Tsunami&amp;rdquo; (L. Krenz et al.) has been accepted for the SC21 Supercomputing Conference.
Read the news piece on the ChEESE website: https://cheese-coe.eu/media/news/cheese-pilot-physics-based-tsunami-earthquake-interaction-paper-3d-acoustic-elastic</description></item><item><title>ChEESE - Center of Excellence in the domain of Solid Earth</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/cheese-flagship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/cheese-flagship/</guid><description>Since November 2018, SeisSol is one of 10 flagship codes of ChEESE, the new European Center of Excellence (CoE) in the domain of Solid Earth (SE). ChEESE targets the preparation of 10 Community flagship European codes for the upcoming pre-Exascale (2020) and Exascale (2022) supercomputers.
SeisSol will be involved in the preparation of two Pilot Demonstrators in ChEESE: Physics-based tsunami-earthquake interaction and Physics-Based Probabilistic Seismic Hazard Assessment (PSHA).</description></item><item><title>SeisSol selected for Student Cluster Competition Reproducibility Challenge</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-scc18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:50:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-scc18/</guid><description>The SC18 Student Cluster Competition has chosen SeisSol and the simulation of the Sumatra 2004 earthquake as the Selected Paper for its Reproducibility Challenge. During the SC18 Award Ceremony, the authors of the respective SC17 paper received a Certificate of Appreciation from ACM&amp;rsquo;s SIGHPC as recognition for reproducible methods and for providing the reproducibility challenge task.
Article by Christopher Bross: https://sc18.supercomputing.org/sc18-announces-selected-paper-for-next-student-cluster-competition-reproducibility-challenge/
Student Cluster Competition: http://www.studentclustercompetition.us/</description></item><item><title>Best Paper Award at SC17</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-sc17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 15:54:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/seissol-sc17/</guid><description>The paper Extreme Scale Multi-Physics Simulations of the Tsunamigenic 2004 Sumatra Megathrust Earthquake (available as open access) by Carsten Uphoff et al. has been selected as SC17 Best Paper.
Articles picking up on this paper include:
GCS NewsFlash: Researchers Create Largest, Longest Multiphysics Earthquake Simulation to Date (article by Eric Gedenk): https://www.gauss-centre.eu/news/research-highlights/researchers-create-largest-longest-multiphysics-earthquake-simulation-to-date Press release &amp;ldquo;New insights into the 2004 Sumatra megathrust earthquake&amp;rdquo;: see reprint on https://www.in.tum.de/en/in/research/research-highlights/2004-sumatra-megathrust-earthquake/ Article in R&amp;amp;D World: &amp;ldquo;Largest Supercomputer Simulation of Sumatra-Andaman Earthquake&amp;rdquo; (by Linda Barney) https://www.</description></item><item><title>Researchers Create Largest, Longest Multiphysics Earthquake Simulation to Date</title><link>http://seissol.github.io/post/researchers-create-largest-longest-multiphysics-earthquake-simulation-to-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://seissol.github.io/post/researchers-create-largest-longest-multiphysics-earthquake-simulation-to-date/</guid><description>We were featured in a research highlight of the Gauss Centre for Supercomputing.
Read the full article: https://www.gauss-centre.eu/news/research-highlights/researchers-create-largest-longest-multiphysics-earthquake-simulation-to-date</description></item></channel></rss>